Nathan Hood

<u>nathanhood@me.com</u> <u>nathanhood.me</u> <u>github.com/nathanhood</u> 615-838-5208 - 204 Croley Court Nashville, TN 37209

Profile

Software developer recently graduated from Nashville Software School

Proficiencies

Object Oriented Programming CSS HTML - Jade - Less - Javascript - Ruby - HAML - Sass Test Driven Development - ERB - Bootstrap - Mocha/Chai/Supertest Version Control with Github - Foundation - RSpec Express/Node.js **Databases** - Capybara/Poltergeist Ruby on Rails - MongoDB - SQL Ajax **j**Query

Skills

Extensive experience managing & participating with teams
Positively represent a company to current & future clients
Self-motivated to complete work with excellence & in timeliest manner possible

Projects

NASHPLORATION

Currently developing Hack4Change winning project. Nashploration is a civic educational application for the City of Nashville to host and implement in schools (<u>nashploration.com</u>).

MUSE COLLECTIVE

The first half of NSS spanned the entire stack, from Node.js within the Express Framework to front-end Javascript, HTML, CSS and more. This project utilizes all this in making a tool for creatives to brainstorm, collect their ideas and collaborate on projects (<u>musecollective.nathanhood.me</u>).

THIRTEEN VIRTUES

The second half of my time at NSS focused on Ruby, Rails, TDD and lower level discussions about object oriented programming. The goal of this application was to hone in my TDD knowledge and better acquaint myself in the Rails environment (thirteenvirtues.herokuapp.com).

Education

Nashville Software School; Nashville, TN - 2014 Hillsong International Leadership College; Sydney, Australia - 2008-2009 Washington State University; Pullman, WA - 2006-2007 (General Studies) North Central High School; Spokane, WA - Class of 2006 Valedictorian

Experience

GENERAL MANAGER, THE MAILROOM, INC; NASHVILLE, TN - JULY 2012 TO APRIL 2014

Promoted to manager of The Mailroom, Inc. dealing with clients, preparing estimates, scheduling daily operations, managing inventories and directly working with the owner of the company on business strategies.

GENERAL LABOR, THE MAILROOM, INC; NASHVILLE, TN - OCTOBER 2010 TO JULY 2012

Started at The Mailroom as a general laborer. Personally handling customer orders, problem-solving, managing online stores, and tracking inventory for clients.